Peter Neagoe Papers
Peter Neagoe Papers
1918-1974
Neagoe, Peter
9.0 linear ft.
Papers of the Romanian American artist, novelist, short story writer (1881-1960). Correspondence, diaries, drawings, manuscripts, photographs, sketches, memorabilia; includes some material relating to Neagoe's wife, painter and muralist Anna Neagoe.
149354
Biographical History
Peter Neagoe (1881-1960) was a Romanian-Amerian artist, novelist, short short writer.
Neagoe was born November 7, 1881, in Transylvania (now Romania). He attended the University of Bucharest and the Romanian Academy of Fine Arts before coming to the United States in 1901 to study at the National Academy of Design in New York. He eventually became a naturalized U.S. citizen, then relocated to Paris following World War I. During World War II he worked for the U.S. Office of War Information, preparing radio broadcasts for the Romanian people. He married married Anna Frankeul, an artist, on July 31, 1911. He died October 28, 1960, in Woodstock, NY.
Neagoe wrote essays, short stories, and novels, many about Romanian peasant life, and edited the periodical New Review as well as an anthology of stories and poems by many of Neagoe's fellow expatriates entitled Americans Abroad. While many of his stories had Romanian settings or characters, he also wrote a number of stories set in America. His characterization and style were praised by critics; regarding his book Easter Sun, a reviewer for the Times Literary Supplement wrote, "Mr. Neagoe writes with an unaffected simplicity perfectly adapted to his subject...and one feels that his peasant characters are created out of an intimate understanding, not merely observed." Neagoe also wrote a book of childhood reminiscences entitled Time to Keep, in which he describes his boyhood in Romania.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Peter Neagoe Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, memorabilia, and writings.
Biographical material contains interviews and essays, as well as several typescript drafts and a published edition of David Sturdevant's monograph on Neagoe.
Correspondence is primarily incoming with a few drafts of outgoing letters, mostly related to the publication of Americans Abroad, an anthology of expatriate prose, and Neagoe's book of short stories, Storm. Correspondence of greatest depth and duration includes that of Djuna Barnes, Alexander Berkman, Kay Boyle, William Aspenwall Bradley, Bob Brown, Whit Burnett, Emanuel Carnevali, John Cournos, John Dos Passos, James T. Farrell, Emma Goldman, Eugène Jolas, Alfred Margul-Sperber, Robert McAlmon, Henry Miller, Edward J. O'Brien, Ezra Pound, Samuel Putnam, Laura Riding, Richard Thoma, Laurence Vail, and William Carlos Williams.
Writings, by far the majority of the collection, comprises manuscripts, typescripts, drafts and notes for more than fifty of Neagoe's stories and novels (both published and unpublished) as well as miscellaneous notes on story ideas. For some titles there are also galleys, camera-ready copy, book jackets, and other material related to production and publication.
Memorabilia includes clippings, diaries, address lists, drawings, photographs (including some used in Americans Abroad), and printed material (issues of magazines containing Neagoe's work).
Separated Material
A number of books by both Peter Neagoe and his wife have been transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Aiken, Conrad, 1889-1973.; Bald, Wambly.; Barnes, Djuna.; Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1902-1981.; Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936.; Boschère, Jean de, 1878-1953.; Boyle, Kay, 1902-1992.; Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1878-1939.; Brancusi, Constantin, 1876-1957.; Breton, André.; Brown, Bob, 1886-1959.; Burnett, Whit, 1899-1973.; Cannell, Kathleen.; Cappon, Alexander Patterson, 1900-; Carnevali, Emanuel.; Charpentier, Albert, 1872-; Coleman, Emily Holmes, 1899-1974.; Cotruș, Aron, 1891-1961.; Cournos, John, 1881-1966.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Crosby, Caresse, 1892-1970.; Diamant, Gertrude, 1901-; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970.; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-1999.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; Foley, Martha.; Ford, Charles Henri.; Fraenkel, Michael, 1896-1957.; Gillespie, Abraham Lincoln, 1895-1950.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940.; Guggenheim, Peggy, 1898-1979.; Hersch, Virginia, 1896-; Jolas, Eugène, 1894-1952.; Jolas, M.; Kahane, Jack, 1887-1939.; Kamin, Martin.; Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-1966.; Larsson, Raymond Ellsworth, 1901-1991.; Lhevinne, Isador, 1896-; Llona, Victor.; Loving, Pierre, 1893-; McAlmon, Robert, 1896-1956.; Mangan, Sherry, 1904-; Margul-Sperber, Alfred, 1898-1967.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980; Neagoe, Anna, 1885-1986.; Neagoe, Peter, 1881-1960.; O'Brien, Edward J. (Edward Joseph), 1890-1941.; Orage, A. R. (Alfred Richard), 1873-1934.; Owens, Philip.; Perlès, Alfred.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972.; Putnam, Samuel, 1892-1950.; Reavey, George, 1907-1976.; Riding, Laura, 1901-1991.; Rodman, Selden, 1909-2002.; Rosenfeld, Paul, 1890-1946.; Schrank, Joseph.; Targ, William, 1907-; Thoma, Richard, 1874-1957.; Vail, Laurence, 1891-1968.; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963.; American fiction -- 20th century.; American literature -- 20th century.; American literature -- Romanian American authors.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Authors, American -- France -- Paris.; Exiles' writings.; Novelists, American.; Painters -- United States.; Expatriate painters -- France.; Romanian Americans.; Paris (France) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; United States -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Audiocassettes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Drawings (visual works); Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Sound recordings.; Novelists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anna Neagoe, 1976-1984.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - General, Jan 1950; undated; includes "Peter Neagoe's Personality," 4pp., translated from Romanian; typescript of interview by Girand d'Uccle, 3pp. (Box 1)
  - "The Most Interesting Man I Ever Met" by Ann Neagoe, 1958; longhand and 2 typescript drafts of a 1-page essay (Box 1)
  - "Peter Neagoe - an Essay and Some Bibliographic Notes" by Donald F. Sturtevant
    - Book, published by Syracuse University Library in 1964, based on materials from the library's collection (Box 1)
    - Drafts, three drafts of essay used in book (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Abernethy, Milton A., 1932 (Box 1)
  - Amzar, Dimitru C., 1946 (Box 1)
  - Bald, Wambly, 1931; Includes photocopy of a correspondence, and photo (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Djuna, 1931-1932; Includes photocopy of a correspondence (Box 1)
  - Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Baxte, Michael und. (Box 1)
  - Bela Bartok Archives, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Berkman, Alexander, 1931-1932; Includes photocopy of a correspondence, and photo (Box 1)
  - Bosschere, Jean de, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Boyle, Kay, 1931-1934; includes photo and photocopies (of the correspondence) (Box 1)
  - Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1931-1934; 1958 (Box 1)
  - Breton, Andre, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1931-1933; 1946 (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Public Library, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Burnett, Whit, 1931-1933; 1936,; 1940-1941; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Brill, A. A. [Abraham Arden], 1932; 1934 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Bob, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Cannell, Kathleen Bigger, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Cappon, Alexander Patterson, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Carneval, Emanuel, 1932; undated; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Charpentier, Albert, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Cheyette, Maurice R., 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - Coleman, Emily Holmes, 1931-1932; includes photograph (Box 1)
  - Cotrus, Aron, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Cournos, John, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Coward-McCann Inc., 1935-1937; 1948-1949,; 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Crosby, Caresse, 1931; undated (Box 1)
  - Cummings, E.E., 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Diamant, Gertrude, undated (Box 1)
  - Dos Passos, John, undated; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Dowling, Allan, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Eliot, T.S., 1932 (Box 1)
  - European Books Ltd., 1935-1937 (Box 1)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1931; 1956 (Box 1)
  - Fagel, Henry Guy, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Farrell, James T., 1931-1935; undated; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Faulkner, William, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Foley, Martha, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Ford, Charles Henri, 1932; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Fraenkel, Michael, 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Friesz, Othon, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Gillespie, A. Lincoln, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Giurgea, Jul, 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - Globe: the International Magazine, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Godwin, Murray, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Goldman, Emma, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Gromaire, Marcel, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1931; 1968 (Box 1)
  - Guillaume, Paul, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Haas, Robert, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Hersch, Virginia, 1932; undated; includes photo (Box 1)
  - International Literary Bureau, 1933; 1935-1937 (Box 1)
  - Jameson, Ruth, 1931; includes photo (Box 1)
  - Jolas, Eugene, 1928-1932; includes photocopies of some correspondence (Box 1)
  - Jolas, Marie, 1931; undated (Box 1)
  - Kahane, Jack, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Kamin, Martin, 1957-1959; undated (Box 2)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Larsson, Raymond E., 1931 (Box 2)
  - Lhevinne, Isadore, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Llona, Victor, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
  - Loving, Peter, undated (Box 2)
  - A. and S. Lyons Inc., 1937-1938; 1940 (Box 2)
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1931-1932; undated; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Mangan, Sherry, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Manguin, Henri, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Margul-Sperber, Alfred, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Mayfield, John S., 1967; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Mencken, H.L., 1932; undated (Box 2)
  - Michel, Albin, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Michel, Albin, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Miller, Henry, 1931-1932; includes photocopies of some correspondence (Box 2)
  - Moreau, Luc-Albert, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Morris, Ira, 1931-1932; 1962 (Box 2)
  - Neagoe, Anna, 1932-1933; regarding art exhibition (Box 2)
  - New York Public Library, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - O'Brien, Edward J., 1932; 1934-1935,; 1940,; undated (Box 2)
  - Orage, A.R., 1928; 1932 (Box 2)
  - Owens, Philip, undated (Box 2)
  - Perles, Alfred, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1931; undated; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Prensky, Eva, 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Putnam, Samuel and Riva, 1931; undated; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Queens Bourough Public Library, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Random House, 1937 (Box 2)
    See also Haas, Robert.
  - Reavey, George, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Riding, Laura, 1931; undated (Box 2)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Romania, 1934; 1937,; 1939,; 1967; includes embassy and consulates (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1931; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Sage, Robert, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Saunders, Marion, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Schrank, Joseph, 1932; undated; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Seabrook, William Buehler, undated; photo only (Box 2)
  - Sperber, Alfred, See Margul-Sperber, Alfred.
  - Stein, Gertrude, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Targ, William, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Thoma, Richard, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Vail, Laurence, 1931; undated; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1931-1932; includes photo (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 2)
- Memorabilia
  - Anna Neagoe, 1973; undated; includes clippings of Anna's art and reviews of her shows; typescript stories "My Dog, Jeffy-Boy," "I am Bored"; published story "The Party" in the April 1974 issue of Image along with a feature on her drawings; story about her in the the August 1973 issue of Image. (Box 2)
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Date Book, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Diaries, documents the Neagoes' arrival and life in Paris; one copy includes margin notes from a reviewer to Anna Neagoe
    - Diary A, circa 1920; 185 pp., original typescript; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Diary B, circa 1920; 185 pp., typescript carbon (Box 3)
  - Drawings, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Drawings, oversize (Oversize 1)
  - Efficiency Rating, Office of War Information, 1943-1944; evaluation from Peter's time as an announcer for the OWI'sOverseas Operations Branch, Eastern Press and Radio Program Division (Box 3)
  - Horoscope, [1918]; typescript, by Angelus Stuart (Box 3)
  - Invitations (Box 3)
  - "Kamin Collection", original folder label; related to Martin and Sally Kamin, a book publisher; includes correspondence, photographs autographed to Sally, one issue of the Air Courier (Box 3)
  - Lawsuit, in Romanian; handwritten note on folder reads "Interesting Lawsuit by Roumanian Professor" (Box 3)
  - Lists of addresses (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - Americans Abroad, photographs of contributors to the anthology (Box 3)
    - Photos of Neagoe (Box 3)
    - Photos of Neagoe, oversize (Oversize 1)
    - Romania, countryside, people, buildings (Box 4)
  - Printed material
    - American Designers Institute roster and directory, 1948 (Box 4)
    - Le Crapouillot, Oct 1932; includes Peter's story, "La Confession de Gavrila", with reproductions of artwork used with the story (Oversize 1)
    - Industrial Designers' Institute roster and directory, 1952 (Box 4)
    - The New Review, Jan/Feb 1931; contains Neagoe's story "They" (Box 4)
    - The New Review, Aug/Sep/Oct [1931?]; Apr 1932; contains Neagoe's story "The Greenhorn"; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Snowy Egret, spring 1962; contains Neagoe's story "Of Men and Beasts" (Box 4)
    - Soldier and the Billy Goat, no. 2 (Box 4)
  - Publicity (Box 4)
  - Reader's reports (Box 4)
  - Stationery (Box 4)
- Writings
  - Books
    - The Adventures of Pacala [unpublished]
      - Draft A, typescript, 150 pp.; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Draft B, typescript copy, pp. 1-80, with critique sheet (Box 4)
      - Draft B, typescript copy, pp. 81-160 (Box 5)
    - Alexander [unpublished]
      - Draft A, pp. 1-180; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Draft A, pp. 181-268 (Box 5)
    - Americans Abroad
      - Reviews (Box 5)
    - Easter Sun
      - Drafts of synopsis, mix of handwritten and typed (Box 5)
      - Advanced reading copy (Box 5)
      - Camera-ready copy (Box 5)
      - Camera-ready copy, book cover (Oversize 1)
      - Contracts (Box 5)
      - Reviews (Box 5)
    - The Greenhorn [unpublished]
      - Draft A, typescript, 235 pp., marked "not like the one published"; two copies, one incomplete (missing pp. 91-117 and 202-235) (Box 6)
      - Draft B, pp. 118-201 only (Box 6)
    - The Icon Maker [unpublished]
      It is unclear what precisely this is. Draft C is a complete story called "The Icon Maker," while Draft A includes "The Icon Maker" as a part of a larger piece called "The Cup of the Devil." There are enough similarities to consider them the same creative piece -- as the same titles suggest -- and yet different enough to be treated separately.
      - Draft A, typescript, 106 pp. (Box 6)
      - Draft B, typescript, 112 pp. (Box 6)
      - Draft C, typescript carbon, 100 pp. (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous drafts, typescript, pp. 38-69 and 82-283, with 3 additional sections labeled as "The Icon Maker" or "taken from the Icon Maker"; envelope holding this marked as "The Icon Maker and Cubin" while pp. 1 has a note "Tentative outline of the biographical novel 'The Cup of the Devil'"; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - No Time for Tears
      - Reviews (Box 6)
    - Povestiri, collection of Peter's short stories (Box 6)
      - Published edition, Editura Dacia, Cluuj Romania, with introduction by Ioan A. Popa, 1972 (Box 6)
    - The Saint of Montparnasse
      - Draft typescript, pp. 1-95 with many notes and corrections; includes correspondence (Box 6)
      - Draft typescript, pp. 96-483 with many notes and corrections; 4 folders (Box 7)
      - "Original Brancusi", longhand drafts (Box 7)
      - "Recollection of Brancusi", contains "My Recollections of Brancusi," theme of the story "The Saint of Montparnasse", and a piece divided into scenes (as a movie would be) with description of the story (Box 7)
      - Galley A (Box 7)
      - Galley B (Box 8)
      - Galley C (Box 8)
      - Galley front matter (Box 8)
      - Reviews (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous research material about Brancusi, longhand and typescript notes about Brancusi; exhibition catalog; section taken from a book; title pages from Peter's book, short typed biography of Brancusi in Romanian (Box 8)
    - A Selection of Stories by Peter Neagoe; arranged with notes by John S. Mayfield
      - Draft (Box 8)
      - Production records (Box 8)
    - Storm
      - Book, Obelisk Press, Paris, bound typescript carbon with stamp on inside cover "As from 1st March 1946 this book is the property of Direct Book Supply Co…."; includes correspondence from donor (Box 8)
      - Contracts (Box 8)
      - Preface, photocopy of preface from book by Eugene Jolas (Box 8)
      - Publicity (Box 8)
      - Reviews (Box 8)
    - There is My Heart
      - Draft, "New Version to be used in Esther's book", includes pp. 204-267, some pages missing; introduction; pp. 13-16 from printed Romanian edition (Box 8)
      - Camera-ready copy (Box 8)
      - Camera-ready copy, book cover (Oversize 1)
      - Contracts (Box 8)
      - Reviews (Box 8)
    - A Time to Keep
      - Camera-ready copy (Box 9)
      - Camera-ready copy, book cover (Oversize 1)
      - Reviews (Box 9)
    - Truth is a Sharp Thorn [unpublished]
      - Draft, typescript, 329 pp.; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Uncle Gerasim [unpublished]
      - Drafts (Box 9)
        Contains:
        Introduction to the Stories - corrections original manuscript 8 p. white type
        Introduction to the Stories - corrections copy 8 pp. white type
        When Nicolai Filiman…6 pp. longhand yellow, 14 pp. white typescript
        When Nicolai Filiman…14 pp. white typescript
        One Has The Letter Another Has The Heart - correct longhand 5 pp. yellow typescript
        One Has The Letter Another Has The Heart, "II" - original manuscript 13 pp. white typescript
        One Has The Letter Another Has The Heart,"II" - copy 13 pp. 3 x 5 card attached com white typescript
      - Drafts (Box 9)
        A Dragon Tamed - corrections longhand 5 pp. yellow typescript
        A Dragon Tamed, "III" - original manuscript 12 pp. white typescript
        A Dragon Tamed, "III" - copy 12 pp. white typescript 3 x 5 card attached
        Uncle Gherasim Catches a Thief - corrected longhand 5 pp. yellow
        Uncle Gherasim Catches a Thief, "IV" - original manuscript 13 pp. white
        Uncle Gherasim Catches a Thief, "IV" - copy 13 pp. white 3 x 5 note attached
        The Source of Fate, "V" - original manuscript 5 pp. white typed
        The Source of Fate, "V" - copy 5 pp. 3 x 5 note white typed
      - Drafts (Box 9)
        Peasant Delegation Sees The Metropolitan - correct longhand 3 pp. white typescript
        Peasant Delegation Sees The Metropolitan, "VI" - original manuscript 12 pp. white typescript
        Peasant Delegation Sees The Metropolitan, "VI" - copy 12 pp. white typescript 3 x 5 card attached note
        Uncle Gherasim Confesses a Sin, "VII" - original manuscript 9 pp. white
        Uncle Gherasim Confesses a Sin, "VII" - copy 9 pp. white 3 x 5 note attached
        Reforming a Braggart - longhand 7 pp. yellow
        Reforming a Braggart, "VIII" - original manuscript 16 pp. white typed
        Reforming a Braggart,"VIII" - copy 17 pp. white typed 3 x 5 card note
      - Drafts (Box 9)
        Uncle Gherasim Writes a Letter to a Politician,"IX" - original manuscript 7 pp. white typescript
        Uncle Gherasim Writes a Letter to a Politician, "IX" - corrected copy 7 pp. white typescript
        Uncle Gherasim Writes a Letter to a Politician,"IX" - copy 7 pp. white typescript 3 x 5 note attached
        A Loose Tongue, "X" - original manuscript 13 pp. white typescript
        A Loose Tongue,"X" - corrections copy 13 pp. white typescript 3 x 5 card
        History - longhand 44 pp. mixed color paper
        There is No Paradise - longhand 10 pp. Yellow
        Uncle Gherasim Looks at Modern Art - corrected longhand 5 pp. white
        Uncle Gherasim Looks at Modern Art - original manuscript 6 pp. white
      - Drafts, additional typescript draft of sections I-VIII (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous notes, longhand 19 pp.
    - The Wheat and its Tare [unpublished]
      - Draft A, original manuscript 185 pp.; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Draft B, typescript carbon, 185 pp. (Box 10)
      - Draft C, typescript, 58 pp., subtitled "Fragment of a Scenario" (Box 10)
    - Winning a Wife and Other Stories
      - Camera-ready copy (Box 10)
      - Camera-ready copy, book cover (Oversize 1)
      - Cover artwork
      - Reviews, scrapbook of clippings (Box 10)
      - Reviews, scrapbook of foreign reviews (Box 10)
      - Reviews, loose clippings (Box 10)
  - Plays
    - Mrs. King
      - Draft, longhand (Box 11)
      - Drafts, typescript (Box 11)
  - Radio scripts
    - [Untitled script], original manuscript 78 pp. longhand and typed yellow & white (Box 11)
  - Screenplays
    - Illeana the Possessed, screenplay by Alyce Pollock from the novel by Neagoe (Box 11)
  - Short stories
    - All for Bread, alternate titles: "The Peasants of Green-Valley to the Bishop", "That God may Give us Rain", "Cry for Bread"; also rendered into verse form by Abe Kramer (Box 11)
    - Alter Ego, alternate title: "Hard-Luck Tom" (Box 11)
    - Arcum-Intensio Frangit; Animum Remissio (Box 11)
    - As God Decrees (Box 11)
    - The Biggest Wolf (Box 11)
    - Big Gods and Little Fishes, an allegory of 1935 (Box 11)
    - Bitter Fruit (Box 11)
    - Blossoming World (Box 11)
      See also material filed under alternate title, His is the Kingdom.
    - Burlac, alternate title: "Gypsy" (Box 11)
    - The Case of the Venial Sin, alternate titles "The Venial Sin" (Box 11)
    - Cherished Hope (Box 11)
    - Damn Fate (Box 11)
    - The Dear Lady (Box 11)
    - Dear Uncle, more like an open letter recounting Neagoe's thoughts and reminiscences of life and philosophy to an imagined uncle; includes longhand pieces, typescript manuscript 134 pp., and a "second version" of pp. 1-48 (Box 11)
    - Dear Uncle, same title as above, but different content (Box 12)
    - Dialogue (Box 12)
    - Dreams of Spring Come True in the Winter, alternate title: "Dreams of Spring" (Box 12)
    - Drum Beat in Harvest Time, longhand original and typescript drafts (Box 12)
    - The Expected Visitor, handwritten note in pencil "This is part of the book which [completed] has 185 pages" (Box 12)
    - Eyes Too Eager, longhand original and typescript drafts; alternate titles: "Plot" or "The Plot" (Box 12)
    - Fading of the Rainbow (Box 12)
    - Fairy Tales by Peter Neagoe, 2 folders
      As the service so the reward
      The fairy queen of the mountains
      Ileana Simziana
      The man of stone
      Only with cattle can a man drive poverty out of his house
      Pacala
      The poor man's clever daughter
      The story of luck
      Tugulea, the lame boy
      Why live fools and bright people mixed in society
      Youth without old age and life without death
    - Forgotten by Gabriel (Box 12)
    - Fortunate Prevision (Box 12)
    - Fortunes of War (Box 12)
    - French translations of stories by Lucienne Escoube (Box 12)
      Les costands de Marseille
      Epilogue
      Une henreuse precaution
      Les jeux du destin
      Josephine